FAHAD SPERINCK

12B Eldon Road, Reading, RG1 4DL sperinck@gmail.com \diamond sperinck.github.io

EDUCATION

University of Reading

Sep 2019 - Present

MSc in Psychology

Provisional result: Distinction

University of Oxford

Oct 2006 - Jun 2011

MMath in Mathematics

Upper Second (2.1)

Dissertation Title: The Bombieri-Vinogradov theorem and its applications

Supervisor: Professor Roger Heath-Brown FRS

EXPERIENCE

Sperinck & Lawson Tuition

Mar 2015 - Jul 2019

Founder and Director

Founded tuition service based in Reading. Led a team of four tutors and built a network of maths and physics tuition clients in Berkshire area

Oxbridge Applications

Aug 2013 - Oct 2015

Mathematics Specialist & Consultant

Delivered talks, seminars, and tutorials. Coordinated MAT/STEP exam preparation events in the UK, Malaysia, and Dubai

BNP Paribas Sep 2011 - Aug 2013

Data Analyst

Created analysis reports for upper management and treasury. Developed in-house Python repositories to automate tasks

RESEARCH & PROJECTS

Sensory history and the contraction bias in working memory

Sep 2019

Neuroscience Data Challenge 2019, University of Bristol

Analysed dataset from an experiment on rats presented with a working memory task monitoring sound amplitudes. Investigated 'contraction bias' effect of sensory history.

Summer Studentship: Stability of infinite Bravais lattices

Jul 2010 - Sep 2010

Oxford Centre for Nonlinear PDE (OxPDE)

Developed an extended atomistic model for stability in infinite Bravais lattices of any dimension, and proved stability in specific one- and two-dimensional examples.

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded Crown Prince International Scholarship from 2006 to 2011.

Awarded Corpus Christi College Scholarship for a First in Moderations, 2007.

William Buckland book prize for excellent performance in college collections, 2007 and 2008.

St Christopher's Prize for Outstanding Achievement in Mathematics, 2005 and 2006.

LANGUAGES

Human: English (native), Arabic (fluent)Programming: Python, Bash, R (proficient)

C++ (working knowledge)

ACTIVITIES

Sound engineer at *The Facebar*, *Reading*, 2015 - Present Lead guitarist in death metal group *Ageless Oblivion*, 2012 - 2014 President of *Oxford University Rock & Metal Society*, 2008 - 2009

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I thrive on solving well-defined problems. My career so far has largely focused on passing on the maths 'bug' to the next generation of mathematicians: the satisfaction of investigation, conjecture and proof, through my own tuition company and others.

My interest in psychology comes after years of repeated exposure to students, friends and family with life-altering conditions. After completing an MSc in Psychology I hope to move into a research role, using mathematical models to solve open problems in neuroscience.